Welcome. In the last lecture, we finished adjusting this climb down ledge animation using Control
欢迎。在上一讲中，我们完成了对这个爬下窗台动画的调整，使用了Control
Brick. And in this lecture, let's look at how we can actually use it. So first, I'm
砖块。在这一讲中，让我们看看我们如何实际使用它。所以首先，我将
going to close my project. Then I'm going to go back to my header file. So I'm going
将关闭我的项目。然后我将回到我的头文件。所以我打算
to create a new anim montage. Copy this one, paste it in here. I'm going to call this one
创建一个新的动画蒙太奇。复制这个，把它粘贴到这里。我将把这个叫做
climb down ledge montage. Then I'm going to go back to my CPP file. So if this condition
爬下窗台的蒙太奇。然后我将回到我的CPP文件中。所以如果这个条件
returns true, I'm going to delete these two debug functions, delete this else case. So
返回真，我将删除这两个调试函数，删除这个else case。所以
if it returns true, I'm going to call the function play climb montage and pass in the
如果它返回真，我将调用函数play climb montage并传入我刚刚创建的
variable that I just created. So it's called climb down ledge montage. And this should
我刚刚创建的变量。所以它被称为爬下窗台蒙太奇。而这应该
do for now. I'm going to compile first. I have a successful compile. I'm going to test
现在就可以了。我先来编译一下。我有一个成功的编译。我打算测试一下
this to see if it actually works. So I'm going to launch my editor back. Go back to my editor
看看它是否真的能工作。所以我准备启动我的编辑器回来。回到我的编辑器中去
before I create a montage based on this animation. I'm first going to double click to open it.
在我创建一个基于这个动画的蒙太奇之前。我首先要双击来打开它。
I think this animation is too long. I'm first going to disable this root motion so we can
我觉得这个动画太长了。我首先要禁用这个根部动作，这样我们可以
better preview it. So for this animation, I don't want these swinging movement, even though
更好地预览它。所以对于这个动画，我不想要这些摆动的动作，尽管它们看起来不错。
they do look good. When we're climbing down, our character will clip through the surface
它们确实看起来不错。当我们往下爬的时候，我们的角色将通过表面的剪辑
and to adjust the length of it. Since this is control relinked, I'm going to do it inside
并调整它的长度。因为这是一个控制连接，所以我将在控制装置内进行调整。
of the control rig. So I'm going to go back to my CRM map, click save, select it, then
控制设备中进行。所以我将回到我的CRM地图，点击保存，选择它，然后
go inside of client system, animation, raw, drop to free hang, double click to open this
进入客户端系统，动画，原始，下降到自由悬挂，双击打开这个
sequencer and I'm going to select this root control and I'm going to scroll forward a
序列器，我将选择这个根控件，我将向前滚动几格
few frames to somewhere near here and we can train animation directly inside of this
几帧，我们可以在这个序列编辑器中直接训练动画。
sequence editor. So I'm going to move this red line to somewhere near here and for this
序列编辑器中训练动画。所以我要把这条红线移到这里附近的某个地方，对于这个
root control, I'm going to move it down a little bit further. So this animation will
根控制，我打算把它再往下移一点。所以这个动画将
push our character down a little bit more to somewhere near here. Alright, something
把我们的角色再往下推一点，到这里附近的地方。好的，一些
like that. Then I'm going to click this button to sync the changes, then go back to my content
像这样。然后我将点击这个按钮来同步这些变化，然后回到我的内容
browser, double click to open this adjusted, open this climb down ledge and you can see
浏览器，双击打开这个调整后的内容，打开这个爬下台阶，你可以看到
we have a shorter animation and that's great. Now I'm going to take this enable root motion,
我们有一个更短的动画，这很好。现在我要把这个启用根部动作、
then I'm going to create a montage based on this. I'm going to rename this to am_climbdownledge
然后我将在此基础上创建一个蒙太奇。我将把这个重命名为am_climbdownledge
and I'm going to go back to my third person map. So go inside of third person maps, double
然后我将回到我的第三人称地图。所以进入第三人称地图，双击
click to open this map, click save selected and before I click play, I'm going to go back
点击打开这张地图，点击保存选择，在我点击播放之前，我要回到
to this climb system, open this character blueprint and I'm going to assign the montage
在我点击播放之前，我要回到这个攀爬系统，打开这个角色蓝图，我要把蒙太奇分配给这个角色。
to the character. So it will be this climb down ledge and click compile and I'm going
给这个角色。所以它将是这个爬下壁架，然后点击编译，我将会
to test this. So I'm going to move to a surface like this and press play. Alright, at a distance
来测试这个。所以我将移动到一个像这样的表面并按下播放。好的，在这样的距离
like this, the condition should return true, I'm going to press F and you can see this
我将按下F键，你可以看到以下情况
is what happened. I'm going to try again. This time I'm going to move a bit closer to
这是发生了什么。我再试一次。这一次，我将移动到更靠近
the ledge and try again. So same issue and that's because the offset distance of these
然后再试一次。所以同样的问题，这是因为这两条线的偏移距离
two line traces, right now they are too far away from the character and the velocity inside
的偏移距离，现在它们离角色太远了，而且根部运动里面的速度
of the root motion is not enough to move our character to the surface in here. So I'm going
的速度不足以让我们的角色移动到这里的表面。所以我打算
to adjust the offset distance, go back to this custom moving component. Now instead
调整偏移距离，回到这个自定义移动组件。现在
of 50, I'm going to lower it down to 20. So this is the offset for the first line trace
而不是50，我要把它降到20。所以这就是第一条线迹的偏移量
and for the second one, the ledge trace, I'm going to lower it down to 30 and click compile
第二条线的偏移量，也就是壁架的偏移量，我要把它降低到30，然后点击编译。
again and go to the surface, press play. And now the condition should return true in here,
再一次点击编译，进入表面，按播放。现在这里的条件应该返回真、
I'm going to press F and you can see it works. I'm going to go to the surface again, but
我要按F键，你可以看到它是有效的。我再去看一下表面，但是
we have another issue. So when we're downplaying the montage, we are now inside of the climb
我们有另一个问题。所以当我们淡化蒙太奇的时候，我们现在是在爬升的
state. We are going to the for loop state directly and to fix that, we need to go back to our
状态。我们直接进入了for loop状态，为了解决这个问题，我们需要回到我们的
code. So instead of the CPP file, I'm going to scroll to the bottom. So on this climb
代码。因此，我不在CPP文件中，而是滚动到底部。所以在这个攀登
montage ended, I'm going to add another or in here. So if this montage is equal to climb
蒙太奇结束后，我将在这里添加另一个或。所以如果这个蒙太奇等于爬
down ledge montage, then I want to call the function start climbing. And for this else
下壁架的蒙太奇，那么我就想调用开始攀登的函数。而对于这个其他
case, I want a more specific condition in here. So I'm going to check if this montage
情况下，我想在这里添加一个更具体的条件。所以我将检查这个蒙太奇是否等于
is equal to climb to top montage. Then I want to set the movement mode to walking. All right.
是否等于爬到顶部的蒙太奇。然后我想把运动模式设置为步行。好的。
I'm going to quickly save all and trigger live coding. Live coding succeeded. I'm going
我将快速保存所有的内容，并触发实时编码。实时编码成功了。我将
to test it again. So go to the surface, press play and go to the ledge, press F. And this
再一次测试它。所以去到表面，按播放，然后去到窗台，按F。
time it works, but we have another issue. So I'm going to go to the surface again, then
这次成功了，但我们有另一个问题。所以，我将再次去到表面，然后
press play and try again. So we are indeed inside of the climbing state when the montage
按播放键，再试一次。所以当蒙太奇结束时，我们确实在攀爬状态中
has ended, but we are also climbing down automatically. And that's because the velocity coming from
的时候，我们确实在爬升状态，但是我们也在自动爬升。这是因为速度来自于
our root motion montage. So to disable that, there's one simple fix. I'm going to go back
我们的根动作蒙太奇的速度。所以要禁用这个，有一个简单的修复方法。我将会回到
to the code again. And instead of this own climb montage ended, other than this start
回到代码中。而不是自己的爬升蒙太奇结束，除了这个开始之外
climbing, I'm also going to call the function start movement immediately. And this should
攀爬，我还将立即调用函数start movement。而这应该
fix the issue. So we'll be zeroing out of the velocity coming from this montage. All
解决了这个问题。所以我们将把来自这个蒙太奇的速度清零。所有的
right. Quickly save all again, trigger live coding. Live coding succeeded. I'm going to
好的。再次快速保存，触发实时编码。实时编码成功了。我将会
try again. So go to the surface, press play, then press F to climb down. And just like
再试一次。所以去到表面，按播放，然后按F爬下去。而就像
that, it's working as expected. So try again. And I can climb down, I can climb up. So I
就这样，它按预期工作了。所以再试一次。而且我可以爬下来，我可以爬上去。所以我
found out that the value of our Z component for our root motion velocity is not high enough.
发现我们的根部运动速度的Z分量的值不够高。
So we'll have an issue like this. I'm going to go to here, press F. And now you can see
所以我们会有这样的一个问题。我要去到这里，按F。
my hands are still above the ledge. So our root motion should move our character a bit
我的手仍然在壁架上面。所以我们的根部运动应该把我们的角色移动到
further down. And there are two ways we can use to fix this. So we can keep decreasing
再往下移。我们可以用两种方法来解决这个问题。所以我们可以不断地减少
the offset distance of these two line traces. If I'm a bit closer to the surface and press
这两条线迹的偏移距离。如果我再靠近表面一点，然后按
F and now it's enough. Or we can go back to the control rig and keep adjusting the root
F，现在就够了。或者我们可以回到控制平台上，继续调整根部的
control. Here I'm going to show you the hard way. So I'm going to adjust the root control
控制。在这里，我将向你展示困难的方法。所以我将调整根部控制
inside of the sequencer. So I'm going to go back to the content folder, open with CRM
在音序器中。所以我将回到内容文件夹，用CRM打开
map and open this drop to frame hang sequencer. Then move to the last frame and select this
地图，并打开这个下降到帧挂的序列器。然后移动到最后一帧，选择这个
root control. So I want to lower this root control a lot more to something like this.
根控制。所以我想把这个根控制降低很多，变成这样的东西。
Then click add key, then sync the changes. Go to file, click save all. Then go back to
然后点击添加键，然后同步修改。转到文件，点击全部保存。然后返回到
my third person map. Double click to open it. All right, go back to my third person
我的第三人称地图。双击来打开它。好了，回到我的第三人称
map. I'm also going to decrease the offset distance for the trace as well. So open this
地图。我也要减少跟踪的偏移距离。所以打开这个
character blueprint and instead of 20, I'm going to lower it down to 15. Lower this one
角色蓝图，我将把它从20降低到15。把这个
down to 25. Click compile. Then go to the surface and press play. And now I'm going
降到25。点击编译。然后转到表面，按播放。现在我将按下F。
to press F. Yeah, I think this time it works a little bit better. And that's pretty much
是的，我想这次效果会好一点。这就差不多了
it. Now we can climb up to the ledge and we can climb down and we can keep moving down.
了。现在我们可以爬到壁架上，我们可以爬下来，我们可以继续向下移动。
If we have reached the floor, we can exit the climb state and we can climb up. Great,
如果我们已经到了地面，我们可以退出攀爬状态，我们可以爬上去。很好、
everything is working really well. Later when you are doing this yourself, you'll need to
一切都运作得非常好。以后当你自己做这个的时候，你将需要
first play this climb down montage in order for this to work apparently. And don't forget
先播放这个爬下的蒙太奇，这样才能明显地发挥作用。而且别忘了
to set your movement mode to climbing when this montage has ended. And you can use the
来设置你的运动模式，当这个蒙太奇结束后，你的运动模式就会攀升。而且你可以使用
functions stop movement immediately to zero out the velocity coming from this root motion.
功能立即停止运动，将来自这个根部运动的速度清零。
If the animation is too long and you want to trim it, you can use the control rig to
如果这个动画太长了，你想修剪它，你可以用控制装置来做
do it there. And same thing goes for this root control. If you need more or less offset,
做到这一点。这个根部控制也是如此。如果你需要更多或更少的偏移、
you know how to control all of that now. Just be patient with it and try not to rush it.
你现在知道如何控制所有这些了。对它要有耐心，尽量不要着急。
Alright, time for you to do it the same and I'll see you in the next lecture.
好了，现在是时候让你做同样的事情了，我们在下一个讲座中见。
[Music]
[音乐]